data is incredibly valuable some call it
the new oil data is what powers most of
the big Tech components and AI models
like chat GPD without data they are
nothing data isn't scarce like oil there
is plenty of it the problem with data is
that it is not organized it's scattered
all across the web data is valuable but
organized data is even more valuable
with organized data you can do academic
research business intelligence market
research content aggregation and more
you can even build old businesses by
just organizing data price comparison
websites extract data from all your
websites and provide value to People by
showing them different prices job board
aggregate job postings from various
websites and stock market dashboards get
news about companies tweets about the
stock price movements and more all from
different websites and display them all
on the same place before we can organize
data we have to collect data one way of
collecting data is by using the official
apis that some some websites provide but
most of the time those apis are either
paid or non-existent this is when web
scraping comes in web scraping is a
method of data collection where we
extract data from websites that do not
provide an API or a direct way to access
the data if you are a data scientist
marketer developer or researcher web
scraping is a tool that you will
eventually need to use to extract the
data you want but of course the
companies that have the data we want
know their data is valuable and they
always make it harder and harder to
scrape their websites with things like
captchas and Bot detection software the
good news for us is that thanks to
scraping browser we can create a
websites without the fear of getting
blocked and that is what I want to show
you today let's pretend you're going on
a trip and you want to find what is the
cheapest day of the week to fly on if we
wanted to do this manually we will have
to go to Skyscanner for example and
manually Click on each day of the week
to see which one has the lowest price
that looks like a process we should be
able to automate using web scraping to
scrape a website like Skyscanner we
would need to automate our browser and
to automate our browser we have many
options we can use selenium playwright
or Puppeteer the good news is that
scraping browser works with all of them
so you can use whatever you want the
Puppeteer code that does what we want
looks something like this here we are
launching Puppeteer which will launch an
automated browser then we are opening a
new tab we have a list of dates we want
to check October 20 21 22 and 23. then
for every date in our list we are
opening the Skyscanner website going
from Seoul to Barcelona plus the date we
are checking we are waiting for 4
seconds and then just for this example
we are saving a screenshot of the page
that has the prices we want to check in
reality you would not take a screenshot
and put this data on an Excel IF I try
to run this code from my laptop the
browser will open but Skyscanner will
detect that I am using an automated
browser so it will block the request and
not show me the page I want enter
scraping browser scraping browser is a
product by bright data the sponsors of
this video scraping browser is a browser
that makes you practically undetectable
when scraping websites and if you get
blocked scraping browser will solve the
captcha automatically for you it has
captcha solving automation built in the
reason why scraping browser is not easy
to detect by other websites is because
it is not a headless browser when you
launch a scraping browser you are
launching a real headphone browser on
bright data servers that looks identical
to the one a real user would use the
scripting browser also has a built-in
proxy monitoring and proxy rotation
which means that every time you launch
the browser you will get a different IP
from a different country making your
scraping even harder to detect bright
data has over 72 million IPS on their
Network which is super useful if for
example you are testing your website and
want to see how it looks like in
different languages or countries using
scraping browser is super simple all we
have to do is change a couple of lines
of code and we're good to go after you
create an account on bright data's
website and you create a scraping
browser you are going to receive three
things post username and a password this
information is all we need to start
scraping using the scraping browser in
our Puppeteer code we will need to
replace this line with this line of code
where the username password and host
variables are what we got from our
bright data dashboard and that is it on
bright data's website you can see how
you can connect if you are using
selenium and Puppeteer or if you're
using python or C sharp with scraping
browser if we run our code we're not
going to see anything in our screen
since the browser has not been launched
in our computer but on bright data's
servers to see how this graving browser
is doing after we run our code we can go
to the scraping browser dashboard where
we got our credentials from and there we
can click on the button that says Chrome
devtools debugger that will give us a
link to the instance of scraping browser
that we're currently running and after
we click it we will be taken to a screen
where we can see the developer tools and
a live view of the browser as you can
see it works like a charm we go to each
page we want to without getting blocked
because some ticket websites change
prices depending on the country to
launch a browser from another country we
could change the connection string a
little bit this connection string will
give us a browser on a random country
this one will launch a browser
specifically from Korea this one
specifically from Australia all we have
to do is write Dash Country dash plus a
two letter country code after the
username and we will get a browser
launched from that place by writing Dash
Country dash EU you will get a browser
from any country inside of the European
Union scraping browser isn't free we
have to pay for the bandwidth we consume
for this reason it is good to only fetch
what we need and not download any
unnecessary images or assets since we're
going to have to pay for it all we can
block URLs so our scraping browser does
not fetch them using Code like this here
we are telling Puppeteer to not fetch
URLs from doubleclick.net or
facebook.com this way when we go to a
page any Google or Facebook ad pixel is
not going to load saving as bandwidth
with the data we've collected from
Skyscanner we could build a travel app
that will display the cheapest places to
travel we can create a price monitoring
tool that will alert us when the prices
are low or we can analyze the data to
find the best seasons to travel on
that's it for this video I hope you
found it useful and I hope you take
scraping browser for a ride keep in mind
that scraping browser can only be used
to create publicly accessible data that
means data that is not hidden behind a
login something to keep in mind to check
out scraping browser click the link
below thanks to Bright data for
sponsoring this video and thank you for
watching as always bye
thank you